Arman Nikkhah Dehnavi

armannikkhahdehnavi@gmail.com

LinkedIn

Researchgate

Google scholar

(+98)9134087103 - Personal Website

ABOUT ME

I am a building science researcher, data analyst and computer programmer with 7 years of experience in Iran. I have a Master's degree in Building Science and have worked on different research projects that require knowledge in both building science and data science. I am also a lecturer in data science for building science in IBPSA-Iran and I try to expand my knowledge in the interdisciplinary fields to develop new approaches in building science.

EDUCATION

Master of science, building science, Shahid beheshti university, August 2020-August 2023

Thesis: The development of the early stage web-based application in building performance simulation (case study: prediction of fire evacuation in public buildings)

GPA:(3.92/4.00)

Bachelor of Architectural Engineering (BSc), Art university of Isfahan, August 2015-August 2020

Final project: The development of the 5D model for a stadium for 3000 people in the southern part of Isfahan. Iran. (BIM approach)

GPA: (3.76 /4.00)

EMPLOYMENT

International Building performance simulation association (IBPSA-Iran)

April 2021- present

Lecturer in data science for building science

- · Taught courses on building science, data analysis, programming, etc. to undergraduate and graduate students
 - · data driven methods in building performance simulation:
 - ·Statistical modeling and machine learning techniques (supervised-unsupervised methods)
 - · python (programming language)
- · Designed course materials, assignments, exams, etc. based on learning objectives and outcomes
- · Evaluated student performance and provided feedback and guidance
- · Engaged in curriculum development and improvement activities
- · Consulting and giving research method advice to students.

University of Shahid Beheshti (SBU)

March 2022 - August 2023

Research assistant, Technical assistant, architecture and urban design department

- · Analyzed data from experiments, simulations, surveys, etc. using various tools and techniques
- · Prepared reports, papers, posters, slides, etc. for dissemination of research findings
- · Collaborated with other researchers, engineers, architects, etc. on multidisciplinary projects

University of Shahid Beheshti (SBU)

March 2022 - August 2023

Technical assistant, architecture and urban design department

· Developed and implemented algorithms and models for building performance optimization and prediction

BSPsim .co August 2021 - present

- · research and development (focused on web-based application in building performance simulation)
- · mid-level python developer
- · junior data scientist

WORK EXPERIENCE

As a developer and researcher:

Fabinnov Innovation Center, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran

July 2020 - August 2021

Role: Researcher – Arduino developer

Project: research about the improvement of children with special needs by architectural design. RANGo is one of our innovations that help children with autism to improve their abilities. RANGo hears a sound from a musical instrument and makes a digital color pencil to paint in touchscreen LCD.

Project: designing an Evaporative Shading System to reduce energy consumption in hot and aired area. performance of the ESS is evaluated in real environment and simulation software.

Building performance research group (PRG), Isfahan, Iran

July 2019 - August 2021

Role: founder -data analyst

Data analyzing in building performance simulation researches - Consulting and giving advice to researcher

As an architect:

More office (Architectural Office), Isfahan, Iran

2016-2019

Role: Co-founder - architect-junior data analyst in building projects

Project: Golsar Gym 2019

Design Collaborated in developing the final design idea. Prepared the design maps. Advised clients on the project feasibility and cost-effectiveness.

Project: Karako Cofe 2018

Design Collaborated in developing the final design idea. Prepared the design maps. Advised clients on the project feasibility and cost-effectiveness.

Project: Joft Shish Cofe

Collaborated in developing a design idea and in the final fabrication.

2017

Project: Heart Health Clinic

Design Collaborated in developing the final design idea. Prepared the design maps. Advised clients on the project feasibility and cost-effectiveness.

2016 Project: MARAL gym

Collaborated in developing the final design idea. Prepared the design maps. Advised clients on the project feasibility and cost-effectiveness.

SKILLS

· Python(programming language)(mid-level)

·AutoCAD (mid-level)

·Arduino (mid-level)

·SketchUp (mid-level)

·SPSS (advance)

·Design Builder (basic)

·Grasshopper (basic)

·smart PLS (mid-level)

·Tensorflow (mid-level)

RESEARCH METHODS

- · machine learning and statistical learning algorithms (advance)
- •generative adversarial neural network(VAE-pix2pix) (mid-level)
- ·convolutional neural network (mid-level)
- ·natural language processing (basic)
- · Optimization algorithms(GA-NSGA2-NSGA3-RBF)(mid-level)
- ·Sensitivity analysis (SHAP) (advance)
- ·Hypothesize tests (parametric and non-parametric test) (advance)
- •Fuzzy inference systems (advance)
- ·structure equation modeling (mid-level)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Scientific journal papers:

Early Design Stage Evaluation of Architectural Factors in Fire Emergency Evacuation of the Buildings Using Pix2Pix and Explainable XGBoost Model

Journal of Building Performance Simulation DOI:https://doi.org/10.1080/19401493.2022.2163422

Targeting modular adaptive façade personalization in a shared office space using fuzzy logic and genetic optimization

Journal of Building Engineering DOI:https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106118

Estimating the Impact of Occupants' Behaviour on Energy Consumption by Pls-SEM: A Case Study of Pakdel Residential Complex in Isfahan, IRAN

Frontiers in Sustainable Cities
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/frsc.2022.700090

Feasibility Study for Poverty Alleviation by Energy Production Through Photovoltaic Panels in Underprivileged Areas of Iran

journal of renewable and new energy

DOI: https://www.jrenew.ir/article 161990.html?lang=en (10.52547/jrenew.10.1.138)

Conference papers:

Compilation of structural components estimation method; Case example: steel and concrete moment frame residential buildings in Tehran (in Persian)

The First International Conference on Built Environment in Digital Age

Application of Machine Learning Methods in the Analysis of Building Emergency Evacuation at Early Design Stages 4th International Conference on Civil Engineering, Architecture, Art and Urban Design

Productivity management of construction machinery in large civil engineering projects of Isfahan Municipality 13th international project management conference

Volunteer Project:

Design for Children with Autism

July 2020 - August 2021

Role: Research, Arduino developer

Location: Fab Lab, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran

•An interdisciplinary research project started with an innovative idea related to human emotions, which led to three prototypes in interactive Serious Game and Design. (Currently in the stage of testing and evaluating in university of Illinoi Urbana Champaign)

RESEARCH INTEREST

Develop new Data-driven method in different types of building performance analysis:

- ·energy consumption analysis in buildings
- ·daylight simulation
- ·fire evacuation
- ·acoustic in buildings
- ·Occupant behavior

COMPETITIONS

Serious Games Competition - SEGAP 2021

September 2021 - November 2021

Organizer: University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran

Design and fabrication of the game prototype, prepared the final maps, documents and the final presentation.

NOVA Competition: (1st place)

September 2020

Organizer: University of Sahid beheshti, Tehran, Iran Developing a web-application named BSP

Evolo Competition

December 2018 - February 2019

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Classes as lecturer (180 student since now):

·Data science and python programming for building science (IBPSA-iran)

2021-present

- ·Mini classes (6 sessions -spring 2021)
- ·summer 2021
- ·winter 2022
- ·summer 2022
- ·winter 2023